http://ontarioparks.com/reservations/privacy

Français
COVID-19 : Get the latest updates on Ontario Parks and COVID-19.
Reservations - Privacy and Security
Reservations
Privacy and Security
Ontario Parks Notice of Collection
Thank you for using the Ontario Parks Reservation and Registration Service. Your trust is important to us and we’re committed to protecting the privacy and security of your personal information. The handling of all personal information by Government of Ontario organizations is governed by the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act.
Ontario Parks is collecting the personal information under the authority of section 29 of the Provincial Parks and Conservation Reserves Act, 2006.
Information we collect
The Ontario Parks Reservation and Registration Service does not automatically gather personally identifiable information. Personal information collected is provided voluntarily by the users of the service. For example, personal information may be gathered in connection with the campsite reservation process.
The personal information you provide will only be used or disclosed for the purposes for which it was collected. Personally identifiable information will not be disclosed or otherwise transferred to unaffiliated third parties.
How we use the information we collect
The personal information collected will help us provide a great Ontario Parks experience. It will be used for the purposes of (1) processing reservations, issuing permits, park administration, management and park enforcement, (2) the fulfillment of orders placed through the online store, (3) the processing of donations and the issuance of tax receipts, (4) Ministry communications and marketing, and (5) Ministry analytics to improve services.
Communication - SMS Messaging
Mobile phone numbers collected as account information may be used by Ontario Parks to send mass SMS emergency messages to alert you in the event of an emergency (like severe weather, wildfire, etc.), during your stay at a park.
Information that is necessary for the use of payment services
Payment card information is collected through a secure connection to process payments and donations in real-time. Payment card information is not stored within the reservation and registration service database.
Cookies
Computer cookies are small files which consist of information. When you visit a website, the website sends the cookie to your computer. Your computer stores it in a file located inside your web browser. This allows the server to carry information from one page of the website to the next e.g. reservations or merchandise in your cart.
The Ontario Parks Reservation and Registration Service uses cookies. You can block or delete our cookies but doing so will prevent you from using all services.
Non-personal data may be automatically collected through the use of “cookies”. Cookies do not contain any information that personally identifies you, but personal information that we store about you may be linked, by us, to the information stored in and obtained from cookies. The cookies used on the website include those which are strictly necessary for access and navigation, cookies that track usage (performance cookies) and remember your choices (functionality cookies).
Security
The personal information you provide that is stored and communicated in the Ontario Parks Reservation and Registration Service is encrypted using Transport Layer Security (TLS). TLS is a cryptographic protocol that provides end-to-end communications security over networks and is widely used for internet communications and online transactions.
More Information
For more information about our Privacy Statement, contact:
For more information on the Ontario’s commitment to protecting your privacy please visit: Ontario Privacy Statement
